<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Sukendhar</title>
 <link href="http://sukendhar.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://sukendhar.github.com/"/>
 <updated>2012-12-15T00:45:00+05:30</updated>
 <id>http://sukendhar.github.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Sukendhar</name>
   <email>sukendhar555@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>What is Ruby on Rails?</title>
   <link href="http://sukendhar.github.com/What-is-ruby-on-rails"/>
   <updated>2012-12-12T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http:/sukendhar.github.com/What-is-ruby-on-rails</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gray&quot;&gt;What is Ruby :&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby is a pure object-oriented programming language with a super clean syntax that makes programming elegant and fun. Ruby successfully combines Smalltalkâs conceptual elegance, Pythons ease of use and learning, and Perls pragmatism. Ruby originated in Japan in the early 1990s, and has started to become popular worldwide in the past few years as more English language books and documentation have become available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gray&quot;&gt;What is Rails:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rails is an open source Ruby framework for developing database-backed web applications.
What’s special about that? There are dozens of frameworks out there and most of them have been around much longer than Rails. Why should you care about yet another framework? What would you think if I told you that you could develop a web application at least ten times faster with Rails than you could with a typical Java framework? You can without making any sacrifices in the quality of your application! How is this possible? Part of the answer is in the Ruby programming language. Many things that are very simple to do in Ruby are not even possible in most other languages. Rails takes full advantage of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the answer is in two of Rails guiding principles: less software and convention over configuration. Less software means you write fewer lines of code to implement your application. Keeping your code small means faster development and fewer bugs, which makes your code easier to understand, maintain, and enhance. Very shortly, you will see how Rails cuts your code burden. Convention over configuration means an end to verbose XML configuration files there aren’t any in Rails! Instead of configuration files, a Rails application uses a few simple programming conventions that allow it to figure out everything through reflection and discovery. Your application code and your running database already contain everything that Rails needs to know!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;
	var disqus_shortname = 'sukendhar';
	// var disqus_developer = 1;
	var disqus_identifier = 'http://sukendhar.github.com/What-is-ruby-on-rails';
	var disqus_url = 'http://sukendhar.github.com/What-is-ruby-on-rails';
	var disqus_script = 'embed.js';
	(function () {
	var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
	dsq.src = 'http://' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/' + disqus_script;
	(document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
	}());
&lt;/script&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
</feed>
